<Document>
# Server Rules
Welcome to Issy's Space Station.

Please read the rules carefully. If you have any questions, join our Discord and create a ticket, or use F1 (AHelp) to contact staff.
Note that F1 (AHelp) only works when admins are online.
We recommend using Discord for non-urgent questions and support requests.

## Core Rules
These rules apply at all times, including between rounds.

- [textlink="Admins have final say" link="A1Admins"]
- [textlink="Behave respectfully" link="A2Respect"]
- [textlink="No discrimination" link="A3Discrimination"]
- [textlink="No shock content" link="A4Shock"]
- [textlink="No sexual content" link="A5Sexual"]
- [textlink="Only use English" link="A6English"]
- [textlink="Don't cheat" link="A7Cheat"]

##New Life Rules

After you die, you can respawn as a brand-new character once a short waiting period has passed. This is a [bold]new life[/bold]: your previous character is gone for good and you start over as someone else.

- You [bold]remember nothing[/bold] from your past life or anything related to this round - no people, places, events, conversations, or grudges.
- You [bold]choose a new name[/bold] and a new identity for your new character.
- You [bold]do not seek out, recognise, or engage[/bold] the person who killed you. Picking your new life specifically to get revenge on your killer is not allowed.
- Acting on knowledge from your previous life (metagaming your own death) is forbidden.

## Role Types
Your role determines which rules apply to you and how. Whether you are a non-antagonist, an antagonist, a free agent, a familiar, or a silicon is only decided by what the game explicitly tells you.

- [textlink="Role Types" link="RoleTypes"]


## Roleplay Rules
These rules only apply during a round. A round ends only when the game returns to the lobby. [color=#ff0000]All of these rules apply fully whenever the game is not at the lobby unless it is in an exempt game mode.[/color]

Roleplay rules do not apply to ghosts/spectators/observers while they are ghosts/spectators/observers. Dead chat is considered to be an in-game out of character chat channel.

- [textlink="Behave respectfully" link="A2Respect"]
- [textlink="Don't abuse out of character knowledge" link="R2Ooc"]
- [textlink="Roleplay your character" link="R3Roleplay"]
- [textlink="Play antagonists responsibly" link="R4Antagonist"]
- [textlink="Follow reasonable escalation" link="R5Reasonable"]
- [textlink="Act professionally as Command or Security" link="R6Security"]
- [textlink="No self-antagging" link="R7SelfAntag"]
- [textlink="No metacommunications" link="R8Meta"]
- [textlink="Use appropriate character names" link="R9CharacterNames"]


## Silicon Rules
You are only silicon if the game clearly and explicitly tells you that you are a silicon. For players who are playing silicons, these Silicon Rules override all roleplay rules if there is any conflict. Silicon Rules do not override core rules.

- [textlink="1. Your silicon laws are rules" link="RuleS1"]
- [textlink="2. Laws must be prioritized by their order" link="RuleS2"]
- [textlink="3. Laws can redefine terms used in other laws" link="RuleS3"]
- [textlink="4. You cannot request or allow a law change" link="RuleS4"]
- [textlink="5. You are a free agent if you have no laws" link="RuleS5"]
- [textlink="6. You are not required to follow orders which are extremely unreasonable" link="RuleS6"]
- [textlink="7. You must remain consistent with your interpretation of laws" link="RuleS7"]
- [textlink="8. Your HUD determines who is crew" link="RuleS8"]
- [textlink="9. Harm refers to physical harm, prioritized by immediacy and likelihood" link="RuleS9"]
- [textlink="10. You may determine how you resolve conflicts between orders" link="RuleS10"]


## Space Law
Space Law is not part of the server rules, but Command and Security are expected to follow it. It governs crimes, sentencing, contraband, search and seizure, and the treatment of prisoners aboard the station.

- [textlink="Space Law" link="SpaceLaw"]
- [textlink="Crime Listing" link="SpaceLawCrimeList"]

</Document>