<Document>
  # Don't abuse out of character knowledge
  Metagaming is the term used to describe actions based on knowledge during a round that is inaccessible to your character. You cannot use information gained while dead or a ghost if you are alive. This does not apply to general knowledge of what antagonists are capable of doing - we expect players to understand what options are available to antagonists.

  ## Knowledge from past lives
  Except when otherwise specified, you cannot use any information gained in a past life in the same round. For example, if you were killed by an antagonist, you cannot warn the crew of said antagonist when you respawn as a mothroach. This does not apply when being brought back from death as the same character, having your brain transferred to another body, or being cloned.

  ## Knowledge that the round will end
  The knowledge that a round will end is out of character information. You cannot pre-prepare for end-of-round griefing (EORG) or perform other actions that only make sense in the context that your character's life ultimately doesn't matter.

  ## Knowledge gained via LOOC
  You cannot use any knowledge gained via LOOC chat that is not in the context of assisting a player with controls, game mechanics, or being made to feel welcome. No in character information should be shared via LOOC, and no actions should be taken or altered because of LOOC or OOC chats.

  ## Do Not Metafriend or Metagrudge
  Giving a person or character preferential treatment based on the events of a previous round is considered metafriending. Treating a person or character negatively based on the events of a previous round is considered metagrudging. Both are prohibited.

  ## Explicitly Not Metagaming
  - Protecting high value crew items (labeled as such), such as the nuke disk, with the understanding that a bad actor may attempt to steal or use them.
  - Remembering the general events of previous rounds, up to the extent that you do not metagrudge or metafriend any other player or character.
  - The fact that antagonists exist and may be present on or off the station in any form.
  - Knowledge of a character's typical appearance.
</Document>
