<Document>
  # Roleplay your character
  Embody your role and play your character as a believable person living on the station. If you are a crewmate, act like one and do your job. If the game has told you that you are an antagonist, then play that role instead.

  - Perform the duties of your role/job. Don't sign up for a job and then ignore it.
  - Respect authority and follow the chain of command. Listen to your department head and to command, and resolve disagreements in character rather than ignoring orders outright.
  - Stay in character. Do not use texting/messaging acronyms (ex: "lol", "wtf", "brb", "lmao", "thx") or emoticons (ex: ":)", "xD") in-character.
  - Do not mention out-of-character (OOC) concepts like game admins or developers in character.
  - Do not use emotes to bypass muted or accented speech, and do not use extremely low effort or impossible emotes.

  ## Examples
  Things you should not do:
  - Say "lol did u c wat just happened" using in-character chat.
  - Say "an admin exploded him" using in-character chat.
  - Emote "motions for you to order guns" or "asks you to order guns in sign language" as a mime.

  Things you could do instead:
  - Say "haha did you see what just happened?"
  - Say "god blew him up" or "centcomm must have bluespaced a bomb to him"
  - Point at the cargo order console then emote "shoots finger guns"

  ## Clowns and goofing around
  Roles like the clown are meant to be silly, and are allowed to goof around and have fun as long as it does not genuinely harm other players or the round. Harmless mischief is fine - it is not an excuse to self-antag.

  Acceptable:
  - Lubricating a floor to slip people for a laugh.
  - Honking, telling jokes, and generally being funny.
  - Harmless pranks that people can shrug off.

  Prohibited:
  - Lubricating a critical area to cause real harm, like the medbay floor during a mass-casualty event.
  - Slipping someone repeatedly to genuinely ruin their round.
  - Using "I'm the clown" as an excuse to break other rules.
</Document>
